STEVEN M. ERICKSON

Marketing Professional

508-579-0764

steven@stevenmerickson.com

stevenmerickson.com

Wrentham, MA



Me are all failures - at least the best of us are. J.M. Barrie

Professional marketer and proud tech geek. I am experienced in developing, executing, and analyzing marketing campaigns. I have a versatile skill set in project management, lead generation, market research, and campaign analysis.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Marketing Programs Specialist

Lenze July 2018 - Present

Responsible for identifying, developing, and managing the integrated marketing programs that support the development and execution of the North American Sales and Marketing plan. Main focus on development and support of Lenze's large network of distributors.

- Maintained and enhanced key tools for distribution network.
- Developed and executed digital marketing campaigns for lead generation and brand awareness
- Led team in Americas market to relaunch e-commerce store.

Associate Brand Manager

LendingClub April 2016 - June 2018

Managed the lead generation efforts for LendingClub Patient Solution's dental business. Gathered industry data and trends to support strategic development of lead generation marketing campaigns

- Managed launches and longer-term maintenance of marketing campaigns in various channels
- Leveraged internal data, lead primary market research initiatives, and accessed secondary research
- Identified opportunities and recommended new media sources, product, process, and pricing improvements

Regional Marketing Coordinator

DENTSPLY Implants

April 2014 - April 2016

Provided education, co-marketing, and collateral support to 40+ sales representatives for their accounts.

- Organized local educational program, tradeshow activities and facility tours
- Developed targeted marketing collateral for sales reps consistent with the corporate brand
- Provided practice development and co-marketing support for key accounts

Associate Marketing Coordinator

DENTSPLY Implants

June 2012 - April 2014

Assited Regional Marketing Coordinators in their efforts to support the sales team.

- Supported local continuing education programs
- Developed custom marketing collateral for key accounts

SKILLS

Software

Adobe Indesign Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Microsoft Office

Languages

HTML CSS Javascript

EDUCATION

B.S. in Marketing

Southern New Hampshire University Apr 2011 - May 2014 3.8 GPA, Magna Cum Laude

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

Native German Italian

INTERESTS

Soccer Cycling Cooking Travelling